<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>thanhngoc.me</title>
    <link href="https://thanhngoc.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://thanhngoc.me" />
    <updated>2025-05-28T18:59:50+07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Thanh Ngoc</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://thanhngoc.me</id>

    <entry>
        <title>The cloth</title>
        <author>
            <name>Thanh Ngoc</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://thanhngoc.me/the-discarded-cloth/"/>
        <id>https://thanhngoc.me/the-discarded-cloth/</id>

        <updated>2025-05-28T12:03:03+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The footsteps grew louder until I saw my father standing in the doorway, brushing the dirt from his old police uniform which was then his gardening uniform. He must have just come back from the garden. I ran to the door and stretched out both&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The footsteps grew louder until I saw my father standing in the doorway, brushing the dirt from his old police uniform which was then his gardening uniform. He must have just come back from the garden. I ran to the door and stretched out both arms to blook it. </p>
<p>"Father, I didn't mean to do it. She chose it herself."</p>
<p>He totally ignored what I said and went straight to the washing platform to clean his feet. I watched the stream of water carry the dirt from his feet, hoping it would be just like my stream of thoughts - never stopping, never settling - so he wouldn't find out what I was hiding. Because if he saw it, I might end up like her. </p>
<p>As always, after washing, he went staight to the hammock. But today, it was already taken -- by her body. Or what was left of it. </p>
<p>She came to our house and lay on the hammock as if it were hers. As if, by calaiming the hammock, she'd claimed out father too. She laughed so loudly it hurt my ears. I covered them, but the sound still pieced through and it was sharp enough to break my last good eardrum. <em>I couldn't let it happen. I had only one eardrum left, and I wouldn't let her tear it apart with that imperious laugh</em>. </p>
<p>I lunged at her and pinched her arm, with all my years of frustration packed into my two fingers. I twisted her skin until I heard a hiss and a rush of air escaping her like a punctured balloon. She deflated. Her neck collapsed, and her head rolled off. It hit the floor and shattered into pieces on the floral Indochine tiles. I was afraid my father would be angry that he'd teach me a lesson. <em>Wasn't she his favorite woman? </em>But when he saw the long-sleeved pajamas and the flat stretch of leftover skin, he didn't even flinch. In fact, he sounded a bit more relaxed than usual. </p>
<p>"Throw this thing out," he said. </p>
<p>It was disgusting to touch so I picked it up with a stick -- the neck skin and all - and dragged it to the landfill. </p>
<p>"Trời ơi! A cockcroach!" My mother screamed. </p>
<p>Out of nowhere, a giant cockcroach among us. </p>
<p>"Use the cloth to catch it." My father demanded. </p>
<p><em>The cloth</em>? I thought. <em>Had the woman finally come down to just a piece of cloth?</em></p>
<p>I threw <em>the cloth</em> over the cockcroach clinging to the wall and grabbed it with both hands. I could feel something squirming. Could it be the cockcroach or the dehyrated skin which was then as thin as a sheet of rice paper? It didn't matter anymore. I crumpled it and tossed it out the window. </p>
<p>Mother signed with relief. Father remained indifferent. We had finally gotten rid of her, and the cockcroach. </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>the scream</title>
        <author>
            <name>Thanh Ngoc</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://thanhngoc.me/the-scream/"/>
        <id>https://thanhngoc.me/the-scream/</id>

        <updated>2025-05-17T12:31:21+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I woke up sweating into the cup of my own palm, my right hand clamped over my mouth as if I had been trying to muffle a scream. I lay there in the dark, heart pounding, throat dry, unsure whether I had screamed aloud or&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="" data-start="299" data-end="535">I woke up sweating into the cup of my own palm, my right hand clamped over my mouth as if I had been trying to muffle a scream. I lay there in the dark, heart pounding, throat dry, unsure whether I had screamed aloud or only dreamed it.</p>
<p class="" data-start="537" data-end="930">I dream often - sometimes three, four times a night. Most of them are dark, unsettling. But only a few I’d call nightmares. There’s one that comes back to me from years ago, when I was ten or eleven. My cousins and I were flying kites in the barren fields behind my house. It was my turn to fly the kite. I took the string and ran, barefoot across the cracked soil. I called out, “Did it fly yet?” But no one answered.</p>
<p class="" data-start="982" data-end="1255">I turned around. The field had become a graveyard. My cousins were gone. The kites fell to the ground. I shouted their names, but the only reply was the mechanical chirping of the crickets. </p>
<p class="" data-start="1257" data-end="1564">I stood there all alone. Behind me, black clouds accumulated and the sky turned dark. In the distance, something stirred. A silhouette. His body was pitch black but his eyes burned red like fire balls. I ran, breathless, down the gravel path beside my house, afraid it would consume me and I would become a shadow too. </p>
<p class="" data-start="1566" data-end="2088">No one came looking. No lights turned on. I ran until my legs gave out. At the end of the road, I saw Tú and Bé, sitting and flicking marbles across the dirt. I cried out to them, and they saw me. “Sister Ngọc!” they shouted, waving at me with a big smile. There and then, the red eyes were gone. But I remembered. I always remembered. Those eyes haunted me for years. I had seen my grandfather on his deathbed that week. I think the shadow was him; that's why I subconsciously addressed the silhouette as <em>him </em>the whole time. Maybe, as a child, that's what death looked like to me. </p>
<p class="" data-start="2090" data-end="2142">But last night, it wasn’t a shadow that came for me.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/12/Screenshot-2025-05-17-at-12.31.00.png" alt="" width="832" height="1006" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/12/responsive/Screenshot-2025-05-17-at-12.31.00-xs.png 640w ,https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/12/responsive/Screenshot-2025-05-17-at-12.31.00-sm.png 768w ,https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/12/responsive/Screenshot-2025-05-17-at-12.31.00-md.png 1024w ,https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/12/responsive/Screenshot-2025-05-17-at-12.31.00-lg.png 1366w ,https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/12/responsive/Screenshot-2025-05-17-at-12.31.00-xl.png 1600w ,https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/12/responsive/Screenshot-2025-05-17-at-12.31.00-2xl.png 1920w"></figure>
<p class="" data-start="2144" data-end="2424">I had just returned home. I remember undressing by the window. That’s always the first thing I do when I get home: I take off my clothes by the window in my apartment on the twelfth floor. I stand there naked for a few moments while looking down at the street below me. I was watching the cars shimmer like fish in a stream when I caught a reflection in the glass.</p>
<p class="" data-start="2426" data-end="2445">I froze.  </p>
<p class="" data-start="2447" data-end="2763">In the reflection, she was standing in the doorway of my bedroom. Another me. She wore a strapless black dress, the kind I’d never wear because I'm afraid my flat chest wouldn’t hold it. Her arms were wrapped tightly across her body, more to keep the dress from slipping than to protect herself. She stared at me - blank and unreadable - as if she wore my face like a borrowed mask. <em>Or maybe it was me who wore her face like a borrowed mask the whole time? </em></p>
<p class="" data-start="2765" data-end="3062">I didn’t move. I didn’t even breathe. I tried to convince myself it was a trick of the light, a result of my imagination. “What if she’s not real?” I whispered. “What if I’m just tired?” Still, I stayed there, naked and stationary. Then, trembling, I turned around fully.</p>
<p class="" data-start="3064" data-end="3078">She was there. Closer now. Right in front of me.</p>
<p class="" data-start="3115" data-end="3274">I startled. Like a heart-fainted spectator flinching at a jumpscare scene. And I screamed myself awake.</p>
<p class="" data-start="3276" data-end="3472">In the darkness of my bedroom, I couldn’t tell if she was still there. But I <em data-start="3353" data-end="3359">felt</em> her. I swear that I <em>felt </em>her. Something shifted.  </p>
<p class="" data-start="3474" data-end="3619">Strangely, even though fear gripped my throat like a second scream waiting to burst, I fell back into sleep as if something had drained the life from me.</p>
<p class="" data-start="3621" data-end="3874">I woke the next morning (thankfully, I still did), but daylight failed to clear the fog from my mind. I remembered vividly where she had stood. And each time I passed that spot, something stirred in me - as if I were walking through her spirit.</p>
<p class="" data-start="3876" data-end="3990">For days afterward, I didn’t dare turn around too quickly, afraid I’d find her behind me again. </p>
<p class="" data-start="3992" data-end="4188">What frightened me most wasn’t her cold face or her silence, but the question of whether the more unsettling is seeing myself standing in front of me, <em>or</em> the fact that I was scared of seeing myself standing in front of me. </p>
<p class="" data-start="3992" data-end="4188">What was she trying to tell me? What truth did she hold behind that mask of indifference?</p>
<p class="" data-start="4190" data-end="4270">And why, when I screamed, did I cover my mouth as if afraid <em data-start="4250" data-end="4255">she</em> might hear me? Is it possible for another self to kill the original and take her place in the waking world? Is she still in my room? Will she come again tonight?</p>
<p class="" data-start="4420" data-end="4447">Was it really just a dream?</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>JACKFRUITS</title>
        <author>
            <name>Thanh Ngoc</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://thanhngoc.me/jackfruits-2/"/>
        <id>https://thanhngoc.me/jackfruits-2/</id>
        <media:content url="https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/11/20200331_102214.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2025-03-18T12:44:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/11/20200331_102214.jpg" alt="" />
                    I woke up with a terrible headache this morning. I reached out for my notebook, trying to write down the dreams I had last night, but the details were all vague and fragmentary. The events were there but they all mixed up and, no matter&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://thanhngoc.me/media/posts/11/20200331_102214.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p class="p2 align-left">I woke up with a terrible headache this morning. I reached out for my notebook, trying to write down the dreams I had last night, but the details were all vague and fragmentary. The events were there but they all mixed up and, no matter how hard I forced my conscousness, I couldn’t conjure up the flow of the story. I was sure my Australian ex-boyfriend was there. So were my first crush from primary school and my families (my parents and, surprisingly, my uncles).</p>
<p class="p2">At one scene, my ex-boyfriend was taking me on a road trip on a Blade Honda scooter that looked like a swiftlet bird. No, actually, it looked more like a swallow as I remembered its trailing forked tail and the red-orange blades. We caught sight of the traffic policemen ahead pulling vehicles over. I asked him to move to the next lane to avoid being caught but he voluntarily stopped at the checkpoint. An officer was tasked with handling his case, giving he was the only could utter some English phrases, and he walked us into a cabin off the road.</p>
<p>- "Show me your bike registration!" He commanded.</p>
<p class="p2">My ex confidently pulled out an A4-sized certificate written Daniel de Filippo on it. <em>"Shouldn't it be his name instead of his good friend's</em>?" I thought to myself but tried to contain my confusion. </p>
<p>- “Now your driving license!” The police added. </p>
<p class="p2">As if he’d been waiting for it to be asked, he took out a plastic card the size of a lottery ticket. The officer examined it and let out a smile.</p>
<p>- “Good good. You are handsome. I’m sure you’ll be a good driver too.” he commented with an effervescent laugh.</p>
<p class="p2">My ex laughed along.</p>
<p>- “Photo? You, me?” The officer asked with his broken English and pointed with his index at him then my ex. </p>
<p>- “Ok Ok”. My ex said excitedly while pulling the officer’s shoulder closer to his and I took a photo of them.</p>
<p class="p2">We said goodbye and were back on the road.</p>
<p>- “We don’t give a damn about these police from now on. We have the photo as our get-out-of-checkpoint-free card.” My ex mischievously declared and I quietly agreed. </p>
<p class="p2">Fast forward to the next scene and I found myself at a wooden sack. (I think my ex-boyfriend dropped me off and disappeared). There were several of them nestled on a hill. It must have been a residency or a guesthouse complex. The sack was basic with a rectangular table, four chairs set on one side of it while the other side pressed against a wall below the only doorless window, and a shrine hung from the ceiling by a chain. The only source of light in the house was from the tiny red LED no bigger than a ghost pepper placed on the head of the Lady Buddha statue on the shrine. She looked down from the shrine, in the bloody aura, with a gentle smile. </p>
<p class="p2">I suddenly remembered why I was there, in the bleak and desolate living room. I was waiting for someone, someone going to murder me as the letter had warned.</p>
<p class="p2">But what letter? When had it been sent and by whom? I couldn’t wrap my head around it. I tried to make up something when I was awake and conscious to reach that gap but nothing was coherent enough. One thing for sure, though, was that someone had sent me a letter foretelling me about me death.</p>
<p class="p2">When I was patiently waiting, which was not at all my nature, my childhood crush, who stayed in another sack behind mine, stuck his head through the window and handed me a bad of air-fried jackfruit.</p>
<p>- “For you to kill time while waiting for your death.” He said and smiled childishly like the old days.</p>
<p>I took no offense to what he said. In contrast, I was pleased with his thoughtfulness. Think of it, his name was literally translated into the Sky or the Heaven. <em>Was Heaven coming to pick me in the shape of my childhood friend? </em>I shook that thought off and took the bag from him. </p>
<p>- “Thank you. Can you keep me company until she comes?” I asked timidly.</p>
<p>- “Of course. That’s why I am here. Honestly, I am curious how <em>she</em> will take you. Tee-hee.”</p>
<p class="p2">I don’t remember how long we’d chatted but as I chewed on the last piece of the crispy jackfruit, we heard someone coming.</p>
<p>- “Is that <em>her</em>?” I could see stars in his eyes and his yellowish teeth sticking out from his mouth.</p>
<p>“Do you think <em>she </em>is chatty?” I asked but he didn’t answer.</p>
<p class="p2">As the chatting voice drew closer, I realized there were more than one person. I leaned against the doorframe, wrapped my arms around and held my elbows with the opposite hands. Before I could see the faces I smelled the unmistakable fragrance of a freshly-picked jackfruit. Then, on the cement winding footpath, a shadow emerged. It was my uncle, my Sixth Uncle, his wife, and my mom.</p>
<p>- “Did you eat yet?” He asked with a familiar unintended coarse voice.</p>
<p>- “Not yet, Uncle.” I smiled.</p>
<p>- “Let’s open this jackfruit. It’s from the garden. Your Mom picked it.” </p>
<p>- “Let’s!” I replied.</p>
<p class="p2">Then he walked to the corner of the room and switched on the light while my mom lit up the incense sticks and fanned it with her hand to put out the flames. The fragrant smoke engulfed her. There, on the tips of the incense only a dot of burning coal was illuminating. She bowed three times and plugged the sticks down into the censer. She turned around and the room lit up.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
